[music]
[laughter]
had to rock the Reds hat, huh?
>> Yeah, man. You feel me?
>> Welcome home. How's it feel?
>> Yeah, it's great. Um, you know, not just
for myself, but my family, you know. Um,
we've been talking about this for a long
time. Being able to come back home and
spend my time like with our family, be
close to our family. You know, my wife,
she's from Jersey, so that's, you know,
not too far from us either. So, I'm just
excited for the opportunity, excited for
the the new the new chapter of my life.
>> Ryan, what do you feel like you bring to
this Bengals team?
>> Um,
I think like like without myself
speaking, um, I would probably obviously
say leadership, that's one thing. Um,
tackling, being consistent. Um, but also
too, I want to put a pin in that as well
because I also want to see my team and
understand like what they really need
from me as well. you know what I'm
saying? I can I am who I am. I want to
bring that to the table, but at the same
time, I also want to learn my teammates
and understand how to make them better
as well. Um, and that will be who I end
up becoming as well. So, every part of
my on my journey is different. Um, here
I say I will be a leader that will be,
you know, that vocal point and that that
anchor um that can they can depend on to
guys to get guys lined up or just have
someone a point of reference when the
bullets are flying. Um, but also want to
be, you know, much more than that, too.
if a guy needs, you know, different type
of uh help or leadership um in any area,
I want to be able to to perform and and
help them with that as well.
>> Is there any guy you watched during your
career who was a leader like that and
you kind of under your wing took you
under his wing or
>> No, I mean the people person like that I
haven't played with. Um like for like
for my reference I would say Reed is
probably like the greatest leader I've
seen um just from afar. But guys that
actually met along the way will be like,
you know, guys like Justin Reed, um Juan
Throwill, um let's go look on Luxurious
Need um people like that. Those people
actually play with um in this journey
and seeing how they only like to take
care of themselves in their body, but
also like their mind and be there for
one another. Um it's a beautiful thing
to see. I'm trying to implement that as
well as um you know, develop my own
skill set as well. How familiar were you
with the safety struggles of the past
few years here in town?
>> Uh I mean my you know my friends they're
uh they're from here obviously and
they're they're biggest fans so they let
me know they let me know. Um but that's
that's not a lot you know I don't I
don't cannot do that to anybody else
anybody's skill set. Um you know
anything can happen within you know a
year. You know we've seen teams come
from being the worst in one the category
to being the best in this category. Um
but I think it's more a technique thing.
Um, I do have my tablet so I can go back
and watch. Um, but like I said, I'd be
more watching to see how can I help them
become better um, from that aspect, but
I understand like maybe it's a struggle,
but you know, like we don't really know,
[clears throat] you know, I don't really
know like why it was a struggle if that
makes sense. I want to know why rather
than just trying to fix something that I
don't really know, you know, like what
caused it.
>> What was their reaction when you told
them or when they found out? Did
>> Oh, they found out? Oh, it went nuts.
Yeah, it went nuts. Like Facebook went
crazy and people don't be on Facebook
like that, you know. I don't. Um, but
Facebook went crazy. My my phone started
blowing up from everywhere. You know
what I'm saying? Um, from from family,
from cousins, from from long-term
friends, from uh uh classmates, you
know, just it's been a it's been an uh a
flame that been, you know, uprooted
since uh the news came out. And so I've
been, you know, basically coasting with
that, you know, uh since then. Um but I
know at the end of the day, like it's
nice, but they're all expecting me to
come in and do something. So I think
that's what like not saying the pressure
because I know like even back in you
know my other team like you know
pressure you know make diamonds. So I'm
excited for that but also know that
there's like a lot of responsibility
that comes with this. Um so I want to
make sure that I'm handling it like the
proper way.
>> What is the key to being a great tackler
from the safety position in your mind
and why do you think that has been a
strength of yours?
>> Um I mean it starts my wife can attend
to that too. It starts with film study.
I mean like you have to like every week
is different. You know, you have your
basics like okay your eyes and and and
your leverage understanding too. You
want to strike half a man. I'm not sure
anybody's in here with boxing. But the
the whole concept of boxing is to be
able to get hit without getting hit or
want to be able to to hit without
getting hit. Same thing with football.
You know what I'm saying? How can I
strike someone in the area that I can
deliver a blow when I'm not crossing my
body week in or taco in, you know, uh
days in uh days out. Um, and then
knowing where to strike, you know what
I'm saying? Um, yeah, understand like
leverage main thing like most guys who
are good tacklers. Um, mostly mostly
play linebacker wrestlers. Um, but for
me, I would also say too like you go
back to film study is understanding how
that person or person carrying the ball,
how they like to run. You know what I'm
saying? And that will kind of put you a
step closer because now you you're
relying on their instincts rather than
just your own. You know what I'm saying?
Um, but that also you do that plus the
the film plus the like the technique
[snorts] aspect for like keeping your
eyes on your target and and striking and
running through. I think also too like
you know it's like don't stop your feet.
That's one issue that even myself had to
grow out of. Um, but yeah, it happens
you know like football we also people at
the end of the day you know we all human
we all flawed. So having the consistency
to be able to do that day day in and day
out, it is a skill and it requires a lot
of work. But you know with the the
proper um habits, it can it can be
turned over really fast.
>> If you look at your journey from only
having one scholarship offer to play
college football [snorts] to now getting
your second contract. We [clears throat]
hear it all the time when you guys get
into the league that the main goal is to
get the second contract. What are you
most proud of in your journey
>> from my first offer to now?
>> Yeah. When you look at your your career
up to this point, what are you most
proud of?
>> Um, I would say the growth, you know.
Um, I've I've played in Super Bowls.
I've I've been there. I got hurt season
injury injuries. um in both aspects
whether NFL and uh in college um I'll
say the journey you know the journey has
helped me become back well become who I
am first but also me you know back here
you know in my hometown to give you know
a light and um you know love and and a
whole different aspect as far as the the
energy we may bring to the city and I'm
from here too so I can understand from a
um a fan aspect or just a a a brother or
friend the joy boy having someone that
you knew at one point, you know, in the
city make it and then to come back to,
you know, add to that. I feel like
that's awesome thing. But the journey as
a whole was probably say my most
precious thing, you know.
>> How much did you
feel the Super Bowl run? You were
obviously at UC, you guys are going to
the college football playoff and all of
that, but what was that? How you
obviously
>> Oh, for the for the Cincy, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, of course you felt it. you
know, we in Clifton and and having a
party, you know, when they uh when he
when he win uh the AC championship and
just having that then plus our own
success, it was just it was just
something that I want to imple uh uh
basically,
how do I put this? I want to have that
happen again, but on a on a different
aspect, on a bigger aspect u but just
not have it one time, I want to have it
consistently. Um so it was a it was
definitely a memory that I will never
forget. Um, but it was just I can't I
still can remember like how me being in
my dorm just hearing like the whole city
just going nuts and just excited and I
it was a it was a joy as a as a person
from here that I can't explain.
>> You won multiple championships in Kansas
City coming here now is was that part of
the draw for you? Do you see this as a
destination where you can win a
championship?
>> Oh yeah, of course. I mean the the one
thing is that you you've done it, you
know. So I think for a lot of people in
life um the the question you ask
yourself is can I can it be done when it
can be done and you did it multiple
times now you're asking how can you do
it differently because time is always
moving um now it's a different challenge
I have a different teammate I have a
different coaching staff you know
different environment
I mean I have you know two kids at this
point too you know what I'm saying so um
it's just it's a different aspect as far
as that that realm but yes I really
believe I can you know we can get it
done again and that's always a goal you
know like why are we doing it for we not
trying to beat best.
>> What do you think of uh Joe Burrow? I
mean, you know, obviously in 2022, I
know you were you were young still.
>> Uh obviously a great AFC Championship
game and the Chiefs won that game, but
what you saw of Joe Burrow, what you
noticed of him, what you still noticed.
What do you think of him? Um, I mean,
first, you know, this isn't a part of
for us like him having a ham and
shoulder pass zone, but I think the
character of him, you know,
>> [snorts]
>> um, I think I believe it was middle of
the game. It was uh, Kansas City was
playing here during the regular season
of that same year. And he took time
during I think like a timeout or I think
there was a flag to speak to me and
just, you know, just he knew who I was.
He knew where I was from and basically
tell me like keep going. You know what
I'm saying? for me as a rookie coming in
especially at that time he thought he
doesn't know that but at the time
probably had like three weeks of just
like I was not figuring it out you know
um it it helped me a lot and so having
that just understanding too for someone
that like the city looks at as like you
know basically the the golden goose um
to be able to be humble enough to to
speak to me in that aspect and and and
[snorts] to support me you know even
when I was on an opposite team um it was
nice and so then that implements now to
when he's out there throwing on
touchdowns and stuff like that. So, it
was exciting.
>> Did you know where you were from? You
know, he knew you were Cincinnati.
>> Mhm. You know, Cincinnati. Um it it was
just how he how he spoke. He's like,
"Are you the sens kid?" I was like,
"Yeah." He said, "Keep it up." You know,
you're doing a good job. It's very
simple, you know, but at the time like
where I was that mentally, I was really
trying to figure out like how like my
place in the league. And I think from
that it was like, "Hey, I'm being I'm
being seen, you know."
>> Has he reached out to you at all yet
since you've
>> Oh, no. No. Well, in the house, so it's
not like
>> Yeah.
>> the craziest thing.
>> Turns the paper by tipping his past the
tea that got
>> Yeah. You know what I'm saying? I I you
know, it's all love, but I I need a ring
that year. So, I hope I can bring one
here, though. That's the thing, though.
>> Did you come to games growing up here,
or was
>> I did my first NFL game I came to, I
forgot what team they playing against,
but it was the coldest game I had been
in, you know, and it was it was so bad.
I think the left second quarter we
stayed for like the warm up and stuff
like that. It was snowing and like it
was building anybody in the stands. Um
but that was my first time really seeing
like you know the atmosphere and stuff
like that and I haven't been in this
this arena since that rookie year. Um
and even then that was so crazy cuz like
by the time I did that I was also very
young. I first came to like my first
game, you know what I'm saying? So
having the years past and playing a
stadium and then now this is my home
stadium, it's it's it's all glory to God
at that point.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Oh, cool. Great. Appreciate it. Le Jack.